I've talked for a little bit and now it's time for you to go ahead and get some practice in.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and push up the branch that I just did.
So I'll be O1 begin and then I'll do a branch right now called O1 exercise.
So that'll basically pick up where we just left off but that way you'll have kind of the latest.
Check out O1 branch exercise for later.
And so the goal here for this particular exercise is you're going to be then
so text area is actually in this particular app use a little bit more than text input surprisingly.
And so I want you to go ahead and take what we've learned so far and to create a base text area component
where we apply basically the things that we learned about as far as like wrapping the component in a vendor
wrapper component you need to go ahead and make it transparent passes attributes and just basically make it work
within the app and then refactor it as you see fit.
And then for those of you that is too easy feel free to go ahead and look at other things that you can
refactor inside of app regarding forms and whatnot.
How did everyone do that work out okay?
All right well if you had any trouble with it no worries we're going to walk through it together.
All right so when it comes to refactoring this part obviously first thing we're going to do is
just kind of see where the text area is being used and so we can see that we have them used in three areas.
So I'm just going to pull from the task form model to start and if we analyze this
DOM element we can see here that besides the text area itself similarly to the import that we saw
earlier the input that we worked with earlier we had a label here and we got a form control.
So I think we have a good place to get started then so I'll go ahead and actually just copy this to
start and then we're going to go ahead and create a new base text area component and so some of
you actually may have noticed that I'm prefacing all of these sort of wrapper components especially
when they're wrapping DOM elements with base you can also wrap prefacing it with your
companies like like two letters that you company name or whatnot but it's generally recommended to do
so because you don't want to conflict directly with any sort of native DOM implementations and so
the general convention is not to use single word component names just to avoid those sort of
future collisions. There's a couple of times review does it natively but again like they're
paying attention to like the spec at a level that most of us probably aren't paying attention to so
it's just one of those things that you'll see that I do sort of as a best practice to avoid that
happening. All right so we got here boom we have this perfect and then what we're going to do here
is we're going to start by just defining the props for the basic things that we want to control
very specifically for so we have things like the label we require true and then we're going to do the
ID again and this I'll remember that I required it unlike last time so we'll make sure to have that
ID and label great so we're going to replace both of these things with ID and then that
didn't work the way I wanted it to so there we go now we found those we got the label here and then
the basically it looks like the main piece we need is we don't need that we don't need to you know
honestly I would like to make the place all there's something that is being sort of alerted to it
is something that we find the a good user experience for people so we'll make that something that's
defined as well and that way it's explicitly here in the component API and then finally we just
got to deal with this description part which we've learned now we don't have to set all that model
value amidst stuff all we got to do is say const basically in this case I can just say model value
equals to find model and then just again just a sprinkling of type grip here the basically the
the greater than less than symbol allows you to pass in what type that you expect to find
model to be so you can see here now define model is a string and so now that we have that we can
go ahead and just find it to model value and then to make sure this works now that everything is good
up we're still missing one thing actually we need to go ahead and define options we're going to go ahead
and just disable the inherent attributes or inherent atters and we're going to go ahead and v-bind
everything else directly to the text area that's the main thing we care about then from here we can
go ahead and jump on in and can refactor this now to base text area so let me make sure this
important correctly I don't think it did oh it did fantastic there's our base text area
although yes that that looks right okay so base text area is imported correctly
now we just need to go ahead and seal this off soft closing we have the ID we have the v model we have
we don't need the class we don't need the rows we have the placeholder and it looks like this one
is still airing out because what did I forget I forgot the label and this one we were just calling
a description so now that should take care of that we don't need any of that boilerplate anymore
and there we go and so to make sure this works obviously this we're currently in the
task form model so let's go ahead and run over to our app let me make sure it's running
that's like it's running all right so we have our tasks our task model here there we go deep
dive into its features this is my new update update task edit here we go and it saves an updated
accordingly so we'll just for the sake of completing the exercise fully we're just gonna quickly
then just do essentially a search and replace so we'll do base text area again I'll make sure
the input is correct leader I think already with that highlight it probably isn't disabled this
good placeholder's good classes good IDs good we do want that label for there I usually like to
put the dynamic stuff a little particularly V model a little bit higher just to let developers know
that's there and then we don't need any of this so that takes care of that and then this is the
time entry form model so the where that is is you'll see that your task can also then
basically track how much time has been added as of this is the time I spend on this component and
then add and you can see here there we go we have our description still working great
and then finally we got one more which is looks like the weak form at models so this one we'll go ahead
and let's drop the label here first this one seems to be airing out the most base text area
delete all that stuff delete delete self-closing delete div don't need the rows don't need the
class save and then I assume it imported correctly but would check nope did not this time
did the type don't know why it does that it seems to be like a 50 50 thing with auto import yep
that one looks good too so the weak form model then on the other hand is when we go to our planter
and we want to look at a week this is where we can add the goals for the week so this is my new goal
update and then it's still here so we're good yes we got a question what is this being saved
to like the database ah the database yes so the way this app currently works is there is a
back-end folder that basically lit and there's a database dot json a db dot json and the way this
is just a static file that's local but combined with this awesome open-line open source library
called json server it studs out a rest API that allows you to basically create mpoints to hit
the shape of the db json and then update it accordingly so it looks like that's good and so I'm
going to go ahead and make sure I commit this to the exercise well it's actually oh one exercise is
where we started so I'm going to check out now oh one solution and then we'll go ahead and add
everything we just did say refactor create base text area component and roof and a place that's fine
actually let's review that okay so for some reason I ID and label are getting passed through
as adders not props in your base text I have defined props yeah okay let's let's let's actually
let's see this actually this is something to so I don't see like I don't see the label
printed on page where it should be the ID works because it's a adder and it's kind of splided
across the rest of the adders works for you so in case anyone is not seeing their attributes show
up so so we see here that the description here is showing up we did a little debugging earlier and so
if you're not using script setup right here and then I think oh I think I'd probably broke it
hold up do you know that should be fine one dev go define off well oh that's how you go there you go
that's that's whatever I said the auto import that's funny okay so let me do this real quick to find props
so I'll explain this to everyone so you're aware of this okay
there we go okay so you'll notice here just recreated the bug that label has magically disappeared right
it looks like everything is fine because after all we've imported all of our themes like our
helpers and so it should work and so this is where I think it's a little bit of a gadget with
the composition API and the new scripts scripts set up a authoring format is that there's actually
let's call it a magic engine running underneath that does a bunch of stuff because we have this
setup attribute added on so even though you theoretically imported these helper methods up here
the compiler isn't there to optimize for those things and therefore it's basically not being caught
and so for those wondering you probably like you might have noticed that I did not actually explicitly
import those and that's just because when you're using scripts setup these macros like define
options define props define model they're just assumed that like you're only using it in the
scripts setup context and therefore you don't need to however just to be clear I think I mentioned
this just before I walked over here that it is totally fine if you want to be explicit for your
developers where these things are coming from and this is not a zoom knowledge there's totally
fine to leave it up here as well but just know that it's not required from like an import perspective
so I had the kind of opposite problem where I had left the label prop off of my base text area
uh-huh and it just loaded up without a label so the requirement of the prop didn't
trigger anything any errors oh interesting so what you're saying just to make sure I understand is that
you left off the prop definition nope the prop definition was there with the required true okay
implemented using the component yeah I didn't include the label as part of like the
props define props that are passed into it and then it was fine and it seemed to be fine it just didn't
render the it just essentially rendered nothing for the label if you didn't have script setup it
would do that because it wouldn't know that it's required because it doesn't actually use it as a
prop yeah but I've got script set it I think no I think let's let's let's let's let's try to
recreate this real quick so I'm in the weak form model you're mentioning that if I delete label
like this right it did not through the error for it refresh at it it did this so yeah just showed up
this honestly might just be like the TypeScript server might need to be restarted
that is something that people actually I guess this is actually worth calling out so in the event
you ever noticing your type inferences are not really working as expected there is this ability
to this one so in your VS code the way I do it is command shift p or if you do command p
basically you're opening your command line and then again for those who are new if you have this
greater than symbol this will basically rather than just like for example if I don't have that
and I just type restart it'll actually look at files inside of my directory the greater than
basically forces it into like command mode essentially and so if you'll notice that if I do a restart
then you'll see view restart view and type flip servers sometimes that's what you need to do in
order to get everything working and so if it's ever looking funky like you're like I definitely
define that correctly why is it so yelling at me yeah try this first this is I I use this quite often
so great questions thanks for calling those things out but yeah this is also what's kind of
interesting about different type checking is that we we technically have the required true as a
prop but because that's a runtime check it won't actually stop like the actual build output
so for those who are wondering and that's one of the reasons why I think we've seen a lot more
code bases opt into the type script is because you want you theoretically want your build to break
if or basically to stop you in the event you have like things that are clearly missing that you've
said is required so you know little things like that but again this is not a type trip course and
so we're sprinkling it in here and there just not getting people familiar with it so there we have that now
whoops okay did I do anything else oh yeah that was just testing and okay great